Guide to the Nevada Legislature Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Nevada Legislature records
1866-1901
WA MSS S-3072
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.92
7 boxes + 1 broadside.
Nevada. Legislature
Arrangement
Arranged by a previous owner into 14 groups. Where possible, these groups have been maintained and recorded in the finding aid. Group 8 does not appear to be present in the records.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Manuscript Senate and Assembly bills of Nevada and related documentation, 1866-1901, documenting proposed, draft, and final versions of laws. Each bill includes annotations by the Clerk of the Assembly or the Secretary of the Senate tracing the successive stages of the bill: when introduced, reported in or out of committee, advanced to first, second, or third reading, ordered engrossed, tabled, voted upon, or otherwise made the subject of legislative action. Laws documented include legislation pertaining to the establishment and incorporation of towns from settlements and mining camps; the jury system; the militia; county boundaries; railroads; mining; labor; river navigation; defense against Indian attacks; carrying concealed weapons; marriage and divorce; and gambling. Also includes manuscript acknowledgments, signed by state officials and governors, for the receipt of state publications, 1866-1877.
Gambling -- Law and legislation -- Nevada; Indians of North America -- Nevada; Law -- Nevada; Legislators -- Nevada; Marriage law -- Nevada; Military law -- Nevada; Mining law -- Nevada; Rairoad law -- Nevada; Railroads -- Nevada; Nevada -- Boundaries; Nevada -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; Nevada -- Politics and government -- 19th century; Legal documents -- Nevada -- 19th century; Legislators -- Nevada -- 19th century; Nevada. Legislature; Nevada. Legislature. Assembly; Nevada. Legislature. Senate
- Group 1: Senate Bills passed and ordered engrossed, 1866-1866; 4 (Box 1)
- Group 2: Original bills passed by the Senate, 1866-1866 (Box 1)
- Group 3: Original bills of the Senate, second session, 1866-1866; 1 (Box 1)
- Group 3: Original bills of the Senate, second session, 1866-1866; 3 (Box 2)
- Group 4: Original bills of the Senate, second session, 1866-1866; 3 (Box 2)
- Group 4: Original bills of the Senate, second session, 1866-1866; 4 (Box 3)
- Group 5: Senate and Assembly bills laid on the table in the senate, second session, 1866-1866 (Box 4)
- Group 6: Senate bills not reported from committee, second session, 1866-1866 (Box 4)
- Group 7: Papers of the Assembly relating to the publication of the debates of the Nevada Constitutional Convention, 1866-1866 (Box 4)
- Group 9: Original bills engrossed, 4th session Assembly, 1869-1869; 2 (Box 4)
- Group 9: Original bills engrossed, 4th session Assembly, 1869-1869; 2 (Box 5)
- Group 10: Original Senate Bills 50-100, 1869-1869; 4 (Box 5)
- Group 11: An act regarding a payment of losses sustained by holders of full paid up fire insurance policies, 1901-1901 (Box 8 (Broadside))
- Group 12: Receipts for journals and reports, 1867-1867; 2 (Box 6)
- Group 13: Receipts for Compiled Laws of Nevada, 1873-1873 (Box 6)
- Group 14: Receipts for Nevada Reports and Statutes of Nevada, 1877-1877 (Box 6)
- Assembly bills, 1869-1869; 3 (Box 6)
- Assembly bills, 1869-1869; 2 (Box 7)